(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-15T20:42:06.599915",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Once upon a time,
there was a girl named Kaela.
She lived alone, along with the nature.
"I need no distraction since I'm here by myself," she said.
She loved to train and work out day and night
to gain the endurance to her own standard.
No one has ever understood what she's been up to.
No one has ever done what she's been doing.
SHE'S UNSTOPPABLE!!!!
At the same time, she claimed herself
to be the coolest blacksmith,
even though she was still the apprentice of a very well-known blacksmith guru.
She also meditated to find the peace that she sought.
On the other hand, she seems like
she didn't like to sleep that much.
WAS IT THE POWER OF THE MAXIMUM RESULT OF THE ENDLESS MEDITATION?!/1!/1?!
WAS IT THE POWER OF THE MAXIMUM RESULT OF THE ENDLESS MEDITATION?!
Still, it's a mystery to be researched for.
She just did everything differently.
Not because she wanted to,
but maybe she just built for that?
I, as the narrator of this story,
hope that people in the future will not say that she's a comedian.
Because she's not...
...right?
Weee!
Weeee, hi, hello!
Hello everyone!
Actually, actually, right, um,
you can see the door besides me, right?
But it's okay,
it's just accessories. It's not even functional.
This is just my normal way to go out from my house.
Yeah, so this is the fairy normal way for me.
Okay, by the way, this is too heavy, let me put this first, okay?
Let me pour water first.
Ah.
Okay.
Now... so many rocks here and there. Okay. Okay. Okay.
Guys, before we start our activity today, we need to drink.
Please hydrate! Remember to hydrate, okay? Hydrate.
Okay, that's also my normal way to drink, okay? Don't judge me by that.
Okay, hold on. This is too heavy.
Ah, I'm ready.
Hold on, why is there so many rocks here? Okay.
Hold on, why are there so many rocks here? Okay.
Okay, hydration skill issue. Skill issue, thank you.
Okay, um now, let me introduce myself first. My name is Kaela Kovalskia, the blacksmith from Hololive ID third generation.
Okay, um now, let me introduce myself first. My name is Kaela Kovalskia, the blacksmith from Hololive ID Generation 3.
Nice to meet you all! Wait, thank you so much for coming to my 3D!
Okay, now what? Now what? You want to see the costume, right? The costume?
Oh, this rocks is annoying. Okay. Okay.
Oh, these rocks are annoying. Okay. Okay.
What what do you want to see? What do you want to see? Slow down? No, I cannot slow down. I don't have patience for that, right?
Okay, be right back. Be right back.
Woah! Woah! We're high! I have no Gatchan right now, see?
Okay. What what what? Hold on, hold on. Galon, galon.
Gatchan, this is my 3D, not Gatchan 3D, okay? Okay, okay.
Gatchan, this is my 3D, not Gatchan's 3D, okay? Okay, okay.
You guys need to look at me, not this Gatchan, okay?
Okay, Gatchan, you know what? Gatchan, stop moving, stop moving. Gatchan, stop moving, okay? Nice.
Now, we need to... You know what, we need to stretch.
We really need to stretch, guys. You need to stretch, too. Stand up, stand up, stand up! Gatchan, you need to follow me, okay?
First thing first.
I don't know if you can... Skill issue.
Skill issue. Mine is better, right, guys? Mine is better, right? Right? Okay.
And then, the next one... Huh.
Oi! Okay. Okay, I think that's enough.
Which one is better? Guys, which one is better? Me or Gatchan? Me, right? Okay.
You know what? There's only one way to see which one is better. Right, so, I we're gonna fight this Gatchan for real, for real.
You know what? There's only one way to see which one is better. Right, so, we're gonna fight this Gatchan for real, for real.
So, this is the time for the battle for the live chat.
There's gonna be a poll. There's gonna be a poll. And then we gonna see which one is better.
There's gonna be a poll. There's gonna be a poll. And then we're gonna see which one is better.
There are three rounds. There are three rounds. The first one is who got the best move.
Right? So, you need to be the judge. Who got the best move?
3, 2, 1, Gatchan, let's go!
Gatchan is winning? This is rigged!
Gatchan MVP, what? I already try my best!
Gatchan MVP, what? I already tried my best!
This is rigged, this is rigged. Okay, okay, okay, that's it.
Enough, that's enough, that's enough.
Before, before I ruin all of the equipments, okay?
Before I ruin all the equipment, okay?
Okay, okay, that's only the first round.
That's only the first one, 76%? Well...
It's fine, that's just the first round, okay?
Yeah, okay...
The second one, the second round, the second round, right?
Who is the most flexible?
Flexible?
What?
Okay, flexible. 3, 2, 1, Gachan, let's go.
Hooaah!
Whoa!
Wait, what is this?
Gachan is doing Kayoung with just one hand?
Gachan is doing a split with just one hand?
What?
Oi.
Hey.
Gachan...
Woah.
Whoa.
Hello guys.
Guys, I can see our skill issue...
...what?
Hey.
Gachan is my ocean up—
Gachan is my...
Oi.
Hey.
Oi. Oi. Oi.
Hey. Hey. Hey.
You know what? Gachan is flexible? That's a lie.
Okay, 71%.
I see how it is. I see how it is. It's fine. It's a 20, but it's okay.
I see how it is. It's fine. It's a 20, but it's okay.
I will definitely win the last one, right? I will definitely win the last one.
I'll definitely win the last one, right? I'll definitely win the last one.
The last one is who is the strongest?
This one, there's no way that Gachan will win, right?
This one, there's no way Gachan will win, right?
Okay, so I will kick Gachan once and Gachan also will kick me once.
Okay, so I'll kick Gachan once, and Gachan will kick me once too.
Okay, you better vote for me, guys. You better vote for me.
Okay, hold on.
1, 2, 3!
Yeaaah!
Yeah!
Free nice.
Pretty nice.
See?
Right?
Hmm...
Okay, okay, kick me, kick me now.
Woah!
Whoa!
Hello, oh, oh.
No, no, no, no. That's that's not the strongest one.
No, no, no, no. That's not the strongest one.
Okay, it's time for you to vote.
Okay, okay, right? Mhm, mhm.
See? What? Let me see the number, the poll number.
See? What? Let me see the poll number.
I see, I see. Skill issue? Hmm.
Okay, you know what? Well, it's a close call. It's a close call. It's fine, it's fine.
Okay, you know what? It's a close call. It's a close call. It's fine, it's fine.
Gachan, you know what? You better pay back that.
Gachan, you know what? You better pay that back.
I challenge you for the next round.
But hmm, I will see. I think I need to do something else.
But hmm, I'll see. I think I need to do something else.
Oh, and now you're running away.
I see.
And Gachan is running away.
Fine.
You know what? Um, I need to take care of this first.
You know what? I need to take care of this first.
I need to fix this.
Woah!
Whoa!
It's done. It's done now.
Right? Now I have the time to catch Gachan again and finish all of my business with her, right?
Right? Now I have time to catch Gachan again and finish all my business with her, right?
So you better stand up first and stretch right now. Adios.
Yay! Guys, guys, I have...
...the beautiful fountain behind me, right?
And can you guess what I'm going to do now? You're right, you're right, yay!
Finally, I have many, many friends with me, Gachan!
Finally, I have many, many friends with me, Gachans!
Gachan!
Wait, I have Gachan with me, right?
Wait, I have Gachans with me, right?
And so, whatever you're doing right now, stand up. You need to stand up together with me and do this together with me, okay? Okay? Ikuzo!
And so, whatever you're doing right now, stand up! Stand up together with me and do this with me, okay? Okay? Let's go!
Adegan tidak dilakukan oleh profesional. Adegan tersebut hanya freestyle semata.
This scene was not conducted by a professional. Some are freestyled.
Actually, you know what, guys?
The full version of that is, I think, 10 minutes something.
You don't need to worry, that's just the introduction of it, right?
That's just the introduction. The full version gonna be uploaded on my channel tomorrow, so make sure that you come back to check it again, right?
That's just the introduction. The full version's gonna be uploaded on my channel tomorrow, so make sure you come back to check it again, right?
Nice! Are you feeling healthy and fit right now? Because we're going to play some roulette right now.
Roulette! Roulette! Right?
So, this roulette, roulette, roulette going to be having some, you know, behind all of this number, there are some posts that I need to do.
So, this roulette, roulette, roulette's gonna be having some, you know, behind all of this number, there are some posts that I need to do.
So, it's actually depends on your luck, guys.
So, it actually depends on your luck, guys.
Okay, without any further ado, let's do this!
Three,
two,
one,
go!
Stop!
Two?
Where's two?
Angy? Oh, no.
Why is the first one it's me to be angry?
Why is the first one supposed to make me angry?
Okay, see? I will be angry right now, okay?
Pamalu! You! Halu! Get some help!
Nice! Nice!
Screenshot already done! Screenshot already done!
Make sure if you have the screenshot, make sure you post it here. The hashtag, okay?
Make sure if you have the screenshot, make sure you post it here with the hashtag, okay?
KaelaKovalskia3D, don't forget anything related to this stream, you can post it here.
#KaelaKovalskia3D. Next one!
Hashtag KaelaKovalskia3D. Next one!
Let's go! Next one! Next one!
Three,
two,
one,
go!
Stop!
Three, What is three?
Wotah! Wotah!
Wotah? Where's the wotah?
I need to drink wotah again. Fine!
I need to drink wotah again. Fine! I see.
Okay. Okay, let's see.
Screenshot time again!
Three,
two,
one,
go!
What is happening?
Hey! I already showered or get some help.
Hey, I already showered! Get some help!
Get some help!
Alright, fair, that's enough.
That's enough.
Okay. Okay, that's enough for now.
Let's go!
Yeah, guys, make sure you don't forget to drink the water too.
Adios.
Got that Adios. 3, 2, 1, go!
Stop!
What's that? What's number one?
No! This one is my favorite. Let's go!
Let's go to sleep, right?
Let's go to sleep now.
Adios. Thank you so much, guys, for coming to my 3D. Bye-bye!
Oi! Oi, don't end my stream!
Oi! Oi, come back.
Hello?
Hello, anyone still here? Anyone still here, right?
Okay, we're still fine.
And by the way, what should I do now?
I don't know why a lot of people keep asking me to sleep.
Every single time I sleep, I always forget what to do.
What is this? Roulette?
Should I spin this? Maybe, right?
I don't know. 3, 2, 1, go!
Stop!
Okay, what's number four?
What's number four now?
Auwo?
Okay.
Auwooo!
What just happened?
Oh.
I see.
I don't know. Okay.
I think that's enough, right?
Okay, this is going to be the last one.
Oh, this is going to be the last one.
3, 2, 1, go!
Stop!
What? No! Ulalala!
Okay, fine. Ulalala.
Okay, for this one, right, you need to make sure that you have the speed to screenshot this, because I will show you ballet moves in a very slow, slow motion.
Okay, we start from here.
Okay. Set! Thank you, thank you, thank you.
Nice.
You got the screenshot already? If you don't get it, well, it's not my fault.
One more time? Okay, I'll give you one more time. You don't need to worry about that.
Okay. Thank you, thank you, thank you!
Okay. If you're lucky enough, maybe someday, some other time, maybe you can see more ballet moves, but if you're not lucky then, well, well, well, well, I don't know.
Okay.
So, what's the next one? What's the next one?
3D is not over yet, guys.
Yeah! Um, 3D without singing will not be enough, right?
Right? So, maybe, maybe, maybe, just maybe I have some guests. I don't know. It's time to move on! Let's go! It's not going to be a comedy one, okay? It's time to be an idol. Let's go!
朝の空を見上げて
I looked up at the morning sky
今日という一日が
and quietly made a wish
笑顔でいられるように
that I'd be able to smile
そっとお願いした
all day today
朝の空を見上げて
Looking up at the morning sky,
今日という一日が 笑顔でいられるように
hoping today will be a day filled with smiles,
そっとお願いした
I quietly made a wish.
時には雨も降って 涙も溢れるけど
Sometimes it rains and tears overflow, but
思い通りにならない日は 明日 頑張ろう
on days things don't go as planned, let's do our best tomorrow.
ずっと見てる夢は 私がもう一人いて
The dream I've always had is of another me,
やりたいこと 好きなように 自由にできる夢
freely doing whatever she wants to do.
人生は紙飛行機 願い乗せて飛んで行くよ
Life is a paper airplane, flying away carrying our wishes.
風の中を力の限り ただ進むだけ
Pushing forward through the wind with all our might.
その距離を競うより どう飛んだか どこを飛んだのか
It's not about how far it goes, but how and where it flew—
それが一番 大切なんだ
that is what matters most.
さあ 心のままに
Now, follow your heart,
365日
365 days of the year.
星はいくつ見えるか 何も見えない夜か
How many stars can you see? Or is it a night where nothing's visible?
元気が出ないそんな時は 誰かと話そう
When you don't feel up to it, talk to someone.
人は思うよりも 一人ぼっちじゃないんだ
People aren't as alone as they think they are;
すぐそばのやさしさに 気づかずにいるだけ
they just don't notice the kindness right beside them.
人生は紙飛行機 愛を乗せて飛んでいるよ
Life is a paper airplane, flying with love loaded on it.
自信もって広げる羽根を みんなが見上げる
Everyone looks up at the wings spread with confidence.
折り方を知らなくても いつ間に飛ばせるようになる
Even if you don't know how to fold it, you'll soon make it fly.
それが希望 推進力だ
That is hope, that is our propulsion!
星はいくつ見えるか
How many stars can be seen?
何も見えない夜か
Or is it a night where nothing is visible?
元気が出ないそんな時は
When you're feeling down,
誰かと話そう
let's talk to someone.
人は思うよりも 一人ぼっちじゃないんだ
People aren't as lonely as they think,
すぐそばのやさしさに 気づかずにいるだけ
they just don't notice the kindness right by their side.
人生は紙飛行機 愛を乗せて飛んでいるよ
Life is a paper airplane, flying with love aboard.
自信もって広げる羽根を みんなが見上げる
Spreading wings with confidence for everyone to look up to.
折り方を知らなくても いつの間にか飛ばせるようになる
Even without knowing how to fold, you learn to make it fly.
それが希望 推進力だ
That is hope, that is our driving force.
ああ 楽しくやろう
Ah, let's enjoy it happily
365日
365 days of the year.
人生は紙飛行機
Life is a paper airplane...
Life is a paper airplane,
願い乗せて飛んで行くよ
flying away carrying our wishes.
風の中を力の限り ただ進むだけ
Pushing forward through the wind with all our might.
その距離を競うより どう飛んだか どこを飛んだのか
Rather than competing in distance, how and where it flew—
それが一番 大切なんだ
that is what matters most!
さあ 心のままに 365日
Now, follow your heart, 365 days!
飛んで行け 飛んでみよう
Fly away, let's try flying!
Yeah! Thank you so much, guys!
Okay, if you guys remember, this song is actually very, very important for me because...
Hmm, I sang this song first time for my one-year anniversary, right? So, yeah.
And look at me now, I'm here today with all of you, I'm so happy! How is it? How is it?
And yeah, by the way, by the way, that's not all. That's...
not all. I still have
so many performances for you,
so don't go anywhere, okay?
Okay, okay.
深い森
[Song: Fukai Mori]
深い 深い 森の奥に
Deep, deep in the forest,
今も きっと
I'm sure even now...
置きざりに した心 隠してるよ
it hides the heart I left behind.
探す ほどの力も なく 疲れ果てた
Exhausted, without even the strength to search,
人々は 永遠の 闇に消える
people vanish into the eternal darkness.
小さい ままなら きっと 今でも見えたかな
If we remained small, could we still see it?
かな
I wonder...
僕たちは 生きる ほどに 失くしてく 少しずつ
The more we live, the more we lose, piece by piece.
偽りや 嘘を まとい
Wrapped in falsehoods and lies,
立ちすくむ 声もなく 彷徨いながら
Standing frozen, unable to even cry out,
生きていく どこまでも 信じてる
We wander on through life, believing no matter where.
光 求め
Seeking the light,
歩き出す 君と今
I start walking with you now.
蒼い蒼い空の色も 気づかないまま
Even the color of the deep blue sky goes unnoticed,
過ぎてゆく毎日が 変わってゆく
As the days passing by keep changing.
つくられた枠組みを越えて 今を生きて
Overcoming fabricated frameworks to live in the present,
錆びついた心また 動き出すよ
Our rusted hearts begin to stir once more.
時のリズムを知れば もう一度飛べるだろう
If we learn the rhythm of time, we can fly once again.
僕たちは
We live our lives,
さまよいながら 生きていく どこまでも
Wandering on to the ends of the earth.
信じてる
Believing,
光求め 歩き出す 君と今
In search of the light, we start walking with you now.
君と今
Walking with you now...
僕たちは 生きる ほどに 失くしてく 少しずつ
The more we live, the more we lose, piece by piece.
偽りや 嘘を まとい
Wrapped in falsehoods and lies,
立ちすくむ 声もなく 彷徨いながら
Standing frozen, unable to even cry out,
生きていく どこまでも 信じてる
We wander on through life, believing no matter where.
光求め
Seeking the light,
歩き出す 君と今
I start walking with you now.
振り返る 道を閉ざし
Closing off the way back,
歩いてく 永遠に
We walk on into eternity.
立ちすくむ 声もなく 生きていく
We live our lives standing frozen,
永遠に
Unable to cry out, for eternity...
Ah, thank you so much Kronii for coming to my 3D!
I'm so happy!
No, thank you for inviting me.
It's such an honor.
And I'm really happy that we get to do this.
Yay, it was fun singing and dancing with you
rather than just playing games!
I mean, playing games are pretty nice too,
but yeah, this was really nice.
I feel like we should do this more often,
you know, when we're given the chance, that is.
True!
So yeah, thank you so much once again,
Yeah, talk to you soon after this, and keep on being amazing.
Bye-bye.
Bye-bye! Thank you, you too! Bye-bye, see ya!
あぁ、目が覚めたら陽が昇り
Ah, when I wake up, the sun rises,
まだまだ眠たい そんな休日
Still so sleepy on a holiday like this.
さあ、焼きたてパン頬張って
Come on, stuffing my cheeks with freshly baked bread,
眠い目擦り 街に繰り出そう
Rubbing my sleepy eyes, let's head out into town!
日向で寝そべって 地面を踏みしめて
Laying down in the sun, stamping the ground,
思うままにステップ踏んで 心が踊り出す
Stepping however I want, my heart starts dancing!
笑顔が溢れてく
Smiles overflow,
心のまま 今日を描く
Painting today just as my heart desires.
鳥は歌って 空を自由に飛び回って
Birds are singing, flying freely through the sky,
猫は走って 気ままにじゃれてる
Cats are running, playfully messing around.
花はそよいで 右に左 風と遊んでる
Flowers sway left and right, playing with the wind.
あぁ 虹が架かる
Ah, a rainbow appears.
ぽかぽか満たされてく 何気ない日常が
Warm and cozy, being filled up by this casual daily life.
髪には花簪 君がくれた大切な物
Flowers in my hair, the precious thing you gave me.
はぁ、たまにはほら落ち込んで 眠れない夜が訪れたり
Ah, sometimes you know, feeling down and sleepless nights visit,
あぁ、見せられないな 腫れた目は 優しい君はすぐ気付くから
Ah, I can't show you my swollen eyes, because kind you would notice right away.
何も出来ずに 外も暗くなって ふっと思い出す 僕のこと呼ぶ声
Without being able to do anything, the outside gets dark, and I suddenly remember the voice calling me.
そうやって日々支えられて 進んでくから また前を向ける
Being supported day by day like that, and moving forward, I can look ahead again.
涙で濡れた日も 笑顔に変わっていく
Even days soaked in tears change into smiles,
僕の心に咲き誇るよ 君がくれた大切な日々
Blooming proudly in my heart are the precious days you gave me.
変わり映えのしない 日常だけど 幸せはほら 降り積もっている
It's an unchanging daily life, but happiness is piling up, you see.
目には見えなくても 掴めなくても
Even if we can't see it with our eyes, even if we can't catch it,
君と僕で一緒にいこう 生きよう
Let's go together, you and me, let's live on.
それでも壊れていく 心はもろいもので 何度も絶望するだろう それでも僕は
Even so, breaking apart, the heart is fragile, we'll despair many times, yet still I...
ぽかぽか満たされてく 平和な日常が ずっと続いていけばいいな そう願って一緒に歌おう
Warm and cozy, peaceful daily life, hoping it continues forever, let's wish that and sing together.
平和な日常が ずっと続いていけばいいな そう願って一緒に歌おう
Hoping that this peaceful daily life continues forever, let's wish that and sing together.
Thank you so much for singing with me!
Thank you, Kaela-holic!
What languages do you want to use today?
あ、日本語？オッケー！
Ah, Japanese? Okay!
わたしは日本語上手？
Am I good at Japanese?
ほんと？ほんと上手？
Really? Really good?
うん、うん、上手！
Yeah, yeah, good!
おお、すごいね！
Oh, amazing!
オーケー、オーケー、オーケー、オーケー！
Okay, okay, okay, okay!
じゃあ、カエラは、どういう食べものが好きですか？
Well, Kaela, what kind of food do you like?
甘いの？
Sweet things?
うん、うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
そう、そう、そう。甘い、すっぱい、すべる？
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Sweet, sour, slippery?
え？苦いの？
Eh? Bitter things?
ピーマン？ピーマン？ピーマン好きなの？
Bell pepper? Bell pepper? Do you like bell peppers?
あ、美味しいの？美味しい、かもしれないけど、うん、うん。
Ah, are they delicious? Delicious, maybe, but, yeah, yeah.
あ、あ、ピーマンは... の... のす...
Ah, ah, bell peppers are... no... no su...
ノス、ノス、ノスキ？スキ？ノー、サンキュー！
Nosu, nosu, nosuki? Suki? No thank you!
ノー、サンキュー、ピーマン！
No thank you, bell peppers!
ああ、インドネシアに遊びに来たら、連絡してね、美味しいものたくさんあるの。
Ah, if you come to visit Indonesia, let me know, there's lots of delicious food.
わ、いいの？何が美味しいの？
Wow, really? What's delicious?
ああ、ナシゴレン、ミーゴレン、ソトアヤマ、サテアヤム...
Ah, nasi goreng, mie goreng, soto ayam, sate ayam...
ああ、さて、カンビン？カンビン？ぐれいカンビン！カンビン、カンビン！
Ah, sate, kambing? Kambing? Gulai kambing! Kambing, kambing!
カンビンって何？あー、カンビン…gimana English-nya itu ya?
What is kambing? Ah, kambing... how do you say that in English?
カンビンは、あ、ひつじです！え？ひつじ？ひつじころカンビン…
Kambing is, ah, sheep! Eh? Sheep? Sheep is kambing...
こわいね！
That's scary!
ああ、カエラは... 悪くないよね？
Ah, Kaela isn't bad, right?
悪いわ！カンビンめっちゅ強調してたぞ！コラ！
I am bad! You emphasized kambing so much! Hey!
箱にあたる陽を横目で眺めて
Viewing the sunlight hitting the box out of the corner of my eye
そっと陰る木の根に一人で比べてた
Comparing myself alone at the roots of a softly shading tree
積もる溜息を吹き飛ばすように
As if to blow away the piling sighs
そんな私を見つけてくれたんだ
You were the one who found someone like me
そうそれは恋のようなぬくもりを
Yes, that warmth like love
君に笑顔咲かせたら
If I made smiles bloom on your face
桜風に踊る空君と出会えたこの場所で
In this place where I met you in the sky dancing in the cherry blossom wind
どれくらいの思い出が溢れそうになるかな
I wonder how many memories are about to overflow
君と流した涙は明日の笑顔の糧にしよう
Let's make the tears we shed together the nourishment for tomorrow's smiles
膝をついてたってほら何度だっていいよ
Even if we fall to our knees, hey, any number of times is fine
意地を張って恥をかいて
Putting up a stubborn front and making fools of ourselves
いじけだってそれでも
Even if we feel dejected, still...
君が傍で見守ってくれたこと
The fact that you watched over me by my side
分かってるから
I know that well.
追い風を受けて止まらない日々も
Even the days when we receive a tailwind and cannot stop
そっと挫けそうになって心がうず巻いた
When our hearts churned as we almost quietly gave up
積もる溜息でまた泣きかけても
Even if we start crying again with accumulated sighs
あたたかな手でずっと支えてくれたんだ
You always supported me with your warm hands
ほら耳を澄ませば一人じゃないから
Look, if you listen closely, you're not alone
諦めかけて心が閉じても
Even if we give up and our hearts close
君が背中を押してくれたよね
You pushed me on the back, didn't you?
You supported my back when I needed it.
春の蕾が花開く頃は
As the spring buds start to open up,
隣で笑い合おうね
let's smile together side by side.
桜風に踊る空君と出会ったこの場所で
In this place where we met, dancing in the cherry blossom breeze,
どれくらいの思い出が溢れそうになるかな
how overflowing with memories it becomes.
君と流した涙は明日の笑顔の糧にしよう
The tears we shed together will feed tomorrow's smiles.
膝をついてたってほら 何回だっていいよ
No matter how many times we stumbled, it's alright.
意地を張って 恥をかいて いじけたって それでも
Putting on airs, feeling embarrassed, teasing each other, but still...
君が傍で見守ってくれたから ありがとうだよ
Thank you for watching over me by my side.
桜風に踊る空君と出会ったこの場所で
In this place where we met, dancing in the cherry blossom breeze,
どれくらいの思い出が溢れそうになるかな
how overflowing with memories it becomes.
君と描くこの花は 未来もきっと残るから
The dreams we sketch together will surely remain in the future.
汗をかいた分はそうさ 強くなれるんだ
The sweat we shed will make us stronger.
Thank you! Thank you for singing with me.
Let's do a challenge!
なに、なに？　チャレンジ？
What? What? Challenge?
Yeah, challenge! challenge!
I will talk in Nihongo, you will talk in a little English!
おー！　エリートイングリッシュ、オッケー！　Come on, come on!
Oh! A little English, okay! Come on, come on!
Okay, 今日、カエラと一緒に歌えるのはどうでしたか？
Okay, kyou, Kaela to issho ni utaeru no wa doushita ka?
うーん、very, very happy! And cry! um... happy cry!
Umm, very, happy, and cry, um... happy cry!
あー。
Ah.
Um, how do you like Japan?
日本とっても大好き！
Nihon totte mo daisuki!
でも、みこちの英語とってもネイティブきべると聞いたので……
Demo, Mikochi no eigo totte mo native kiberu tte kiita node...
みこちから英語を学びたい！
Mikochi kara eigo o manabitai!
えっ？　どこでそんなに英語覚えてきたの？　そうね……
E? Doko de sonna ni eigo oboete kita no? Souna...
のののの、みこネイティブじゃないけれどね、ちょっと……ね？
No no no no, Miko native ja nai keredo ne, chotto... ne?
日本の夏のおみわいは一番最高です！
Nihon no natsu no omiwai wa ichiban saikou desu!
英語でなんていうの？
Eigo de nante iu no?
えっ？　日本の夏の一番最高です。
E? Nihon no natsu no ichiban saikou desu.
Summer Japan is so good!
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah! Yay!
Yay!
大丈夫かな？
Daijoubu ka na?
みこちの英語じょうず、まだ……
Mikochi no eigo jozu, mada...
色々学びたいけど時間がなくて悲しい。また遊ぼね！
Iroiro manabitai kedo jikan ga nakute kanashii. Mata asobo ne!
今日は来てくれてありがとう！
Kyou wa kite kurete arigatou!
英語こそThank you for inviting me! カエラ！
Eigo koso Thank you for inviting me! Kaela!
おめでとうね！　また遊ぼね！
Omedetou ne! Mata asobo ne!
Ah, thank you! またね！　またね！
Ah, thank you! Mata ne! Mata ne!
Tangled up in knots,
feeling lost in this uncertainty
Frustrated, caught in
twists of this life complexity
thrown myself in the backseat since forever
tangled up in knots, feeling lost in this uncertainty
frustrated, caught in twists of this life complexity
thrown myself in the backseat since forever
been riding the roller-coaster of insanity
my soul is craving for peace
it's getting hard to breathe
suffocating in the grip of my shattered dreams
chasing rainbows, drowning in shattered moonbeams
tears streaming down, i'm searching for reasons why
i'm breaking free
from these chains
no matter how hard it gets
i gotta keep on moving
you can't take my life away
i just wanna be free, please set me free
let me be me
barely survive in this
ocean of inconsistency
i'm the emotional storm,
longing for simplicity
thrown myself in the backseat since forever
i'm drowning in the ocean of my own frustration
in the darkness, i lost my way
those laughs keep echoing
suffocating in the grip of my shattered dreams
chasing rainbows, drowning in shattered moonbeams
no one to blame but me, myself and i
i'm breaking free
from these chains
no matter how hard it gets
i gotta keep on moving
you can't take my life away
i just wanna be free, please set me free, let me be me
set me free...
tears streaming down, i'm searching for reasons why
no one to blame but me, myself and i
isn't it surprising?
Okay, so that was my original song, Backseat.
So, yes, I wrote the lyrics by myself, so if you want to get the details of that song, I can definitely tell you whole of it on my post-talk stream.
By... Putomo-san, arigatou, arigatou.
And, yeah, the MV going to be there
And yeah, the MV's going to be there
really, really soon after this stream, so make sure you listen to it again.
There's also subtitles there.
So please, please, please, please check that out. I worked so hard for it. So yeah.
And also, you know what? Um, before we continue,
I don't know if you guys already know my pejongsenin stream, right?
I don't know if you guys already know my Pejong Senin stream, right?
So, I mean, I know that I'm a blacksmith. I am called Blacksmith,
but, you know what, I also can listen to your problems.
If you want to fight for yourself, too, I can be there for you.
Please come to the pejongsenin stream to know me more, and also, you know what?
Please come to the Pejong Senin stream to know me more, and also, you know what?
This is a name card for you. That's actually a free sample, okay?
That's actually a free sample. And actually, yes, this is my merch, my 3D merch.
And hold on, I'll make sure that the banner will come out in the right way here, right?
Hello?
Okay, I get it right this time. Okay, so this is...
Okay, I got it right this time. Okay, so this is...
my merch, and I can show you some magic again, okay? Opened!
my merch, and I can show you some magic again, okay? Open!
Whee! Very nice. Okay, so this is the inside side...
Whee! Very nice. Okay, so this is the inside...
side of the card case, if you really want to get the real one,
not only the free sample one, it will be sold after the holoh3ro 3D collab, right?
not only the free sample one, it will be sold after the HoloHero 3D collab, right?
You know what, it's not over yet. My 3D is not over yet. This is my merch.
And hold on, okay? Hold on, be right back.
Okay. Oh, this is it. This is actually the hardest part for me.
Okay, so what is it now?
Yeah, what is this? That's so big.
So, maybe some of you know already that actually writing has been a very big, big impact for my life before I met games.
Yeah, I didn't just play games after I born, you know?
Yeah, I didn't just play games after I was born, you know?
I used to grind in writing so much, and writing kind of saved my life in somehow, some way.
So I personally wrote something for all of you, for Pemalau, for all of you, for everyone that really, really support me so much,
So I personally wrote something for all of you, for Pemalau, for all of you, for everyone that really, really supports me so much,
and actually, this is my last performance for tonight.
I just hope that I will not cry, right?
Okay, okay, okay, let's go, let's do this, let's do this. I can do it, right? I can do it.
Ada malam di mana aku bertanya,
There is a night when I ask,
Apa maunya semesta dunia ini dariku?
What does this universe want from me?
Ada pagi di mana aku tidak lagi ingin melihat matahari.
There is a morning when I no longer want to see the sun.
Karena aku tahu, aku harus berjuang lagi di hari yang tidak pasti.
Because I know, I have to fight again on an uncertain day.
Tapi itu dulu.
But that was then.
Sekarang aku sadar, kunci kebahagiaan hidup itu bukan untuk dicari.
Now I realize, the key to happiness in life is not to be sought.
Kebahagiaan itu tidak disediakan secara cuma-cuma untuk kita yang terlena di kenyamanan.
Happiness is not provided for free for those of us lulled in comfort.
Jika kita inginkan bahagia, maka kita yang harus menciptakannya.
If we want happiness, then we are the ones who must create it.
Aku tahu itu takan mudah.
I know it won't be easy.
Mereka hanya bilang, kita harus kuat.
They only say, we must be strong.
Tapi kuat itu yang seperti apa?
But what kind of strong is that?
Kuat itu yang bagaimana?
How is that strong?
Kuat itu ada di dalam diri kita sendiri.
Strength is within ourselves.
Mungkin hidup kita tidak akan selalu baik-baik saja.
Maybe our lives won't always be fine.
Tapi dengan kita terus mencoba, mencoba untuk terus hidup,
But by us continuing to try, trying to keep living,
mencoba untuk terus berbenah diri,
trying to keep improving ourselves,
Itulah definisi kuat.
that is the definition of strong.
Terima kasih.
Thank you.
Terima kasih sudah selalu ada.
Thank you for always being there.
Pahit manisnya perjalanan ini
The bittersweetness of this journey
Sampai aku bisa ada di sini hari ini,
Until I could be here today,
malam ini
tonight,
semuanya berkat kalian.
is all thanks to you guys.
Semuanya untuk kalian.
Everything is for you guys.
Kalian adalah bagiannya aku.
You guys are a part of me.
Kalian adalah kuatnya aku.
You guys are my strength.
Jadi... terus kuat ya!
So... keep staying strong, okay!
3D Showcase Special Announcement